I've always wondered, what did Jesus mean by, in my father's house there are many mansions
and in the house of my father there are many more houses.
You can prepare a place for each other.
It means that in my father's house there are many homes.
So if we're talking about a human body, we're talking about organs and cells.
If we're talking about Noah's Ark, we're talking about the rooms.
We're building a Mariological Space Ontology and a Zettelkasten of GitHub repositories.
It means Jesus isn't dead because he's gone to prepare a place for us.
So when people say Jesus is dead, they're saying altruism doesn't exist.
They're saying everyone is motivated by their own greed and narcissism.
They're saying there's no such thing as a jackalope lantern.
They're saying...