In the depths of my mind
A twisted world unfolds
A canvas painted dark with stories
Yeah, I'm told
Dreams of Francis Bacon
His brushes dipped in pain
A crony of madness
Driving me insane
The strokes are jagged
Like fractures in my soul
A portrait of chaos
Where shadows take control
Visions of despair
Distorted faces scream
A dance of the deranged in my sleepless dream
In the dark of the night
The colors come alive
A symphony of torn and brightness
Blind lost in the labyrinth of Bacon
A twisted mind
In the dark of the night
The colors come alive
A symphony of torn and brightness
Blind lost in the labyrinth of Bacon
In the dark of the night