erase my memories erase my mind gotta leave the past behind i don't remember what i used to be
i'm breaking free from my history forget the pain forget the tears i'm wiping clean all my
feelings no looking back i'm on my own in this amnesiac so
lost in a haze but nothing's real i feel a picture i can't really feel
i'm searching for something i can't recall the memories won't let me fall
so
am i still in the now feeling the flow my mind expanding like an helisepco
phenomenology i'm breaking them all exploring dimensions my thoughts unfold
awakening senses like a vibrant symphony oh because i'm shining through my destiny
i dive deep within to find my true breaking down barriers breaking through
the world's a canvas where i paint my dreams with no limits to this universe as far as it seems
i'm applying it drawing my own path the fresh don't wake me i'm free