In the dead of night, when the moon is high
Reckles hit the streets, raiders scouting Joe and I
They gather in packs like a thieving crew
Stealing all the garbage, leaving nothing for you
Trash cans on the corner, they can't resist
Sneaking through the alleys that they don't exist
Their little parts searching for a midnight feast
Turning up the neighborhoods and chaos in the streets
Reckles don't give a damn, they're on a mission
Infections trapped, causing a lot of incoherence
They move so stately, they feast in the night
Feeling all left, told us it's their delight
It's their delight
In the dead of night, when the moon is high
Reckles hit the streets, raiders scouting Joe and I
They gather in packs like a thieving crew
Stealing all the garbage, leaving nothing for you
Trash cans on the corner, they can't resist
Sneaking through the alleys that they don't exist
Their little parts searching for a midnight feast
Turning up the neighborhoods and chaos in the streets
Reckles don't give a damn, they're on a mission
Infections trapped, causing an urban collision
They move so stately, they feast in the night
Feeling all left, told us it's their delight
It's their scouting behind you, in the garbage
Truly pressed, covered in grime
Eyes gleaming with light, a scavenger of the streets
In the talk I take
Infections trapped, causing an urban collision
They move so stately, they feast in the night
Feeling all left, told us it's their delight