Drossing my thoughts, thoughts, philosophers, blind, each inviting
Darkness shining so bright, nihilistic notions taking over my mind
In this life's chaos, leading's hard to find
Existential questions, they keep me alive
Through the turmoil and struggles, I will thrive
Searching for purpose in this world absurd
Dancing with nihilism, my truth has burned
In the depths of existence, I find my release
Rigid on river, my heartbeat won't cease
It stands to the tune of philosophical bliss
Embracing our questions, sweet ignorance we kiss
Let us know
As of existence, I find my release
Rigid tone rhythm, my heartbeat won't cease
Let's dance to the tune of philosophical bliss
Embracing our questions, sweet ignorance we kiss