Don't guess, no rules, it's life's line
You just know it's got me feeling so fine
Breaking free from all the illusion
All the lies, living in the moment
Don't need to compromise
Now you listen, got me questioning it all
Every belief, every step, every fall
Life's a dance on the edge
The past is an act, it breaks in the void
Even judgments in the past
Beyond the lens in the past
Beyond illusions
We find our own way
In this crazy world we make the rules that we obey
No existential crisis, we choose to exist
Doing it our way
In this life we persist
You just know it's got me feeling so fine
Breaking free from all the illusion
All the lies, living in the moment
Don't need to compromise
Now you listen, got me questioning it all
Every belief, every step, every fall
Life's a dance, it breaks in the void
Even judgments in the past
Don't need to compromise