Lines of cold are running through my mind
Syntax are lying in its own rhythm, I can't hide
If you made it at the time, what digital sanctuary?
Write melodies in a code repository
Tabs and spaces, dancing on the screen
Auto-complete makes some music so lean
Indentation like a bass drops so deep
As I navigate through the Kogakene
Go to the beat, so symphony in my hands
The melody turned my own to nickel man
From lights to melodies in a digital screen
Falling to the rhythm in perfect harmony
Full day and night, live stream, white text, light
Wanna write just write, lines clean out of sight
Escape to commemoration, KL roads
Jump lines with these keystrokes
Syntax, no joke
Rims forever so sleek
Mentalistic peak, typing makes my heart beat
No mouse, just rhythm and streak
Short cuts that I crave, mastery I crave
All inside my cave, editing with wave
Facing in the breeze, yanking such a tease
I'm sure we do it with ease, make it please or please
Jump lines with these keystrokes
Syntax, no joke
Rims forever so sleek
Mentalistic peak, typing makes my heart beat
No mouse, just rhythm and streak
Facing in the breeze, yanking such a tease
I'm sure we do it with ease, make it please or please
Go to the beat, so symphony in my hands
Come to the beat, a symphony in my hands
Thin and in love I dance, the melody to my
Four eyes to mech, command, command
From life to next to life
Come to the beat, a symphony in my hands
Thin and in love I dance, the melody to my hand
Thin editor, my ultimate command
From lines to melodies in a digital spree
Coating to the rhythm in perfect harmony
Code all day and night
Black screen, white text like
Wanna ride just right
Lines green out, it's life
It's state to command mode
H-shaped K and L roads
Jump lines with these keystrokes
Syntax, no joke
Looking for ever so sleek
Middle of a listic beat
Siphon makes my heart beat
No mouse, just rhythm and streak
Short cuts that crave
Mastery, I breathe
All inside my cave
Everything with weight
Facing in the breeze
Yanking such a tease
I'm sure we do it with ease
Make it please or please
Symphony in a breeze
Mastery, I breathe
All inside my cave
Everything with weight
Facing in the breeze
Yanking such a tease
I'm sure we do it with ease
Make it please or please
Think forever
Last stream
All I'm
All inside
My cave
Editing with weight
Pacing in a breeze
Yanking such a tease
I'm sure we do it with ease
Make it please or please
Think forever so sleek
Middle of a listic beat
Siphon makes my heart beat
No mouse, just rhythm and
Think forever so sleek
Middle of a listic beat
Siphon makes my heart beat
No mouse, just rhythm and
streak
Go to the peace