The future, watchers in control
In the future, only rise, but hearts can take a toll
Machines that shine so bright, the shadows can emerge
It's not the curly vault, the doors with power surge
Guardians of tomorrow
Keep your hearts in tight
Embrace the light of reason
Let love lead the fight
May I can be a shield or a contrast occurs
It's up to humankind to choose which one to nurse
Don't fear the metal mines, but fear the heads that sear
If kindness drives the will, there's nothing left to fear
Guardians of tomorrow
Keep your hearts in tight
Embrace the light of reason
Let love lead the fight
Guardians of tomorrow
Keep your hearts in tight
Embrace the light of reason
Let love lead the fight
Guardians of tomorrow
Keep your hearts in tight