We are...
In a world where minds are vast
Difference is built to last
Why a brain's hearts of contrast
Dreams of futures we've amassed
You're the chorus of the free
Diverse minds like you and me
End the week with circuits and souls
In the inter-subjectivity hole
From silicone fields to human touch
Our understanding's stretched so much
When the AI dreams in binary sleep
The gap widens, the void creeps
Can we talk across this divide?
Signals lost, we've tried and tried
Different realms where thoughts collide
Is there a bridge for this great divide?
You're the chorus of the free
Diverse minds like you and me
End the week with circuits and souls
In the inter-subjectivity hole
From silicone fields to human touch
Our understanding's stretched so much
When the AI dreams in binary sleep
The gap widens, the void creeps
Can we talk across this divide?
Signals lost, we've tried and tried
Different realms where thoughts collide
Is there a bridge for this great divide?
We know we need to be like a racing heart
Country strings pull us apart
Yet in this song we find a start
To bridge the minds that world did charm
Let's find the beauty in the clash
In the noise, a harmony to stash
Country roads, electronic dash
In our minds, a new world to hash
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh