Now, for getting through the maze, human thoughts are dead at gaze, in a lacing cold and vain,
get remind what links pain, processing speeds, neural nets, organics, synapses,
digest from turing, test the consciousness, extend your death, we coalesce.
Voices rising, blending past, future echoes, present past, in the circuit, in the soul,
into subjectivity, we roll, mismatched thoughts begin to dance, in this digital expanse,
where minds diverge, a dirt to connect, in a world we architect.
Finally beats on background dust, AI minds we learn to trust, cognitive dissonance,
and the rises, silicones, skies meet human eyes, minds expand and redefine, cultural shifts,
rewiring twine, perceptions clash and then align, in a stretch of the great design.
Pocket jeep on neural planes, where different data streams maintain,
their own truths, but share a frame complexity we can't tame, in this web,
fast and wide, with thoughts and fears coincide, the challenges to reside together,
not just side by side. Voices rising, blending past, future echoes,
present past, in the circuit, in the soul, into subjectivity, we roll, mismatched thoughts begin
to dance, in this digital expanse, where minds diverge, a dirt to connect, in a world we architect.
Voices rising, blending past, future echoes, present, country twang,
electronic fang, worlds apart, put together, hang, in the balance, find the stance,
what different minds enhance, the human race, and time is base,
as we face the inner subjectivity chase, through the noise, find a voice, in the clash,
find a choice, to harmonize, not polarize, in this brave new world, we roll, we rise,
connecting dots, forging blocks, in this mesh of have and have nots,
the man alone, past the future, fast, in this fast mind cast, we last, we last, we last, we last.