The whistle blows before the dawn I rise up from my bed of straw
Another day, another yawn In a world that's ruled by iron law
My hands are raw, my back is bent My boots are worn from miles of tread
The factory calls, the hours spent To earn the crust that keeps me fed
Deep by toil and sweat Breathing dust and the bitter scent
The gears keep turning, I can't forget This life is hard, but my soul's not spent
The chimney smoke clouds up the sky And the students tear-sting in my eye
But I'll fight on till the day I die Just a cog in this great machine
The children sleep in the corner room Their stomach's empty, their cheeks so thin
My wife stitches by candle's gloom Hoping one day we might just win
A fireless hearth, the night's so cold I hold her close, but she don't weep
We've both grown tired, we've both grown old Wishing for dreams we could never keep
In shadows, deep by toil and sweat Breathing dust and the bitter scent
The gears keep turning, I can't forget This life is hard, but my soul's not spent
The chimney smoke clouds up the sky And the students tear-sting in my eye
But I'll fight on till the day I die Just a cog in this great machine
The masters watch from windows tall Their world of glass and touch by grime
While down below we risk it all Our lives are spent today at a time
But somewhere out beyond these gates A better world may lie ahead
Where men aren't bound by heavy weights And children sleep in proper beds
In shadows, deep by toil and sweat Breathing dust and the bitter scent
The gears keep turning, I can't forget This life is hard, but my soul's not spent
The chimney smoke clouds up the sky And the students tear-sting in my eye
But I'll fight on till the day I die Just a cog in this great machine
And if one day the whistle fails And the gears grind to restless halt
Then we'll tip the scales And find the strength to make it our fault
Until that day I work and breathe Among the clamour, steel and steam
Just a man who dares believe In more than this great grinding machine