I saw headlights in the night, moving fast, new and in sight.
That old twisted glass display, in a heartbeat changed my life.
Silent screams and teary eyes, that I stood and questioned why.
When the dust had cleared away, I was left to face the day.
Shattered dreams, all around, all the hope lost in a sound.
In the winds I hear the call, echoes of the one to fall.
But my heart still beats in sight, through the storm I will abide.
From the ashes I will rise, with the spirit by my side.
I'm the one who made it through, with our hearts still black and blue.
Living for those lost too soon, dancing in the sorrow moon.
Every breath I take is theirs, carried by the whispered prayers.
I'm the voice of shouts unheard, healing wounds that never bled.
Every step you've bittersweet, walking on this lonely street.
Memories like those they cling, of the night that clipped my wings.
Yet I cherish every beat, in my chest despite defeat.
For my soul will carry on, singing their unwritten song.
In the silence of the stars, I find stars in my skies.
For the moment, just the pain, they're the proof of what remains.
I will never be the same, but I wear this patch of flames.
My first tale, kept alive, echoes in the darkest nights.
I'm the one who made it through, with our hearts still black and blue.
Living for those lost too soon, dancing in the sorrow moon.
Every breath I take is theirs, carried by the whispered prayers.
I'm the voice of shouts unheard, healing wounds that never bled.
I'm the one who made it through, with our hearts still black and blue.
Living for those lost too soon, dancing in the sorrow moon.
Every breath I take is theirs, carried by the whispered prayers.
I'm the voice of shouts unheard, healing wounds that never bled.
Never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never, never