debunking GPT, genius, prodigy, and talent.
This book critically examines myths about child geniuses and prodigies,
emphasizing the significant role of deliberate practice and complex interactions between young
learners and adults. It challenges the belief that extraordinary abilities are solely good to innate
talents, and explores how adult interactions can subtly influence children's perceived ability.
Demonstrating this point, the book delves into historical anecdotes like clever Hans.
The horse believed the perform arithmetic tasks by tapping his hoof.
Investigations revealed that Hans was actually responding to involuntary cues from his observers,
not understanding mathematics. Similarly, McFosh's goat was thought to nod in agreement to questions.
But this behavior was orchestrated via a hidden mechanism, not any cognitive processing by the goat.
These cases parallel how adults can omit and recue children to give expected responses,
potentially distorting assessments of a child's true cannibalism,
not any cognitive processing by the goat.
These cases parallel how adults can omit and recue children to give expected responses,
potentially distorting assessments of a child's true capabilities,
and overshadowing the importance of consistent, focused practice.
The text further explores how socioeconomic factors crickily shake access to educational
resources and social capital, which profoundly affects a child's development.
It advocates for monotonically increasing non-hierarchical learning environments.
When education is tailored to the child's case and interests, promoting natural growth and
exploration without predefined bedspots. Additionally, the book discusses the
psychological strategies of liking and blocking, the fostering engagement,
the possible emotional responses, and focusing efforts on limiting distractions.
These cases parallel how adults can omit and recue children to give expected responses,
potentially distorting assessments of a child's case and interests.
Additionally, the book discusses the psychological strategies of liking and blocking,
fostering engagement, the possible emotional responses,
and focusing efforts on limiting distractions.
These strategies are crucial for making motivation,
intellect and efforts to what's needed.